Come, Sherlock.
You should eat.
Oh, I'm fine. I ate
too much last night.
You've put on some weight.
'Bout half a stone, I'd say.
[gasps]
[WATSON]
He noticed that?
[knocking]
- -[door squeaks]
- -Huh?
Sherlock. You've a visitor.
[WATSON grunts]
I'll come down.
Yes? Can I help you?
Good morning to you.
Might Mr. Holmes be in today?
[WATSON]
Indeed. You must be a client.
Come in.
[MYCROFT] Not to be rude,
but you shouldn't overindulge.
You seem to have gained
about half a stone of late.
What?! But just how
would you know that?
[MYCROFT] I noticed the
buttonholes on your vest
have been enlarged.
The tailoring appears
to be rather hasty,
so seems it was
a recent change.
Factoring in your
waist size and height.
It's quite clear to see that
you have gained half a stone
[grunts] Who the devil are you?
[MYCROFT grunts]
[HOLMES grunting]
- -[HOLMES grunts]
- -[MYCROFT chuckles]
[grunts]
[HOLMES grunts, gasps]
[WATSON gasps]
Sherlock!
[HOLMES groans]
Huh?
[MYCROFT chuckles]
[MYCROFT] Today's test
makes it 673 to nothing, Sherly.
I'm left to wonder...
How much longer before
you make me taste defeat?
[WATSON grunts]
Soon enough, Brother.
[WATSON gasps]
This man is your brother?
Lamentably so.
My elder brother, Mycroft.
Delightful, isn't it?
A new revolver developed
by my unit that shoots paint.
[HOLMES]
Who cares? Get out!
[WATSON]
Pardon me.
Are you truly
Sherlock's brother?
[HOLMES]
Tch.
Indeed.
My brother and I have taken
very different paths in life.
What do you want?!
Did you come here solely
to make snide remarks?
I'm actually here to give
you a warning, Sherlock.
[WATSON]
Beware of women, dear brother.
Wha--?
Seeing through the
deceits of the fairer sex
is even more difficult than
tracing the threads of a crime.
Well, I shall be
taking my leave now.
Reflect upon my advice, Sherly.
[HUDSON giggles]
[WATSON grunts]
You're looking rather pale.
Are you feeling poorly?
[HOLMES]
Mycroft has that effect on me.
[WATSON]
That carriage he's traveling in.
Is he employed in
some government office?
Some office?
It's not nearly so simple.
No. He is the government.
In the flesh.
He sounds important.
[HOLMES groans] Let's stop
talking about my brother, 'kay?
Instead, look at this.
Read it.
It appears undated,
without signature or address.
[WATSON] "There will
call upon you tonight,
at a quarter to eight o'clock,
a gentleman who
desires to consult you
upon a matter of the
very deepest moment.
Be in your chamber
then at that hour,
and do not take it amiss
if your visitor wear a mask."
[HOLMES]
Your thoughts, John?
First, this handwriting
is that of a man.
Further, I believe him to be a
well-educated man of means.
This particularly fine paper
could not be had for less
than half a crown, I'd say.
See? You can do it if you try.
Now then, about the paper.
Hold it up to the light.
[WATSON] Are these the
initials of the paper mill?
[HOLMES] The "PGt" is
German for Papiergesellschaft.
It means paper company.
"Eg" most likely
stands for Egria,
A city in Bohemia's
German region.
[WATSON] So the man
who sent you this letter
is a masked German
from the Kingdom of Bohemia.
Is that right?
[knocking]
[MYCROFT]
Yes, come in.
[door opens]
[MYCROFT] Forgive me
calling for you this late.
[MYCROFT]
Lieutenant Colonel Moriarty.
Sir, what does the director
of the intelligence service
need with me, an officer
of the Indian Army?
[MYCROFT]
I understand that you, Colonel,
with limited manpower,
secretly wiped out
the distribution routes
of that new kind of opium
making its way around London.
[ALBERT] Hm. An internal
investigation, sir?
[MYCROFT]
Yes. And as a result,
I found your qualifications
to be quite sufficient.
[MYCROFT] I would appreciate
your assistance in this matter.
[MYCROFT] Irene Adler.
An American,born in New Jersey.
Retired following a
career as the prima donna
of the Imperial Opera of Warsaw.
Publicly, she is well
known as a former actress.
But secretly she's a courtesan,
with a multinational
clientele of nobility.
I'm tasking you
with the retrieval
of certain classified
papers stolen by this woman.
These classified papers--
they are more than just
correspondence, I gather.
What they contain could
be far more devastating
than you can imagine,
I assure you.
It concerns the Crown, and the
stability of the Empire itself.
[ALBERT]
Whoever retrieves these papers
will unavoidably learn
the contents within.
If he's making such a determined
effort not to reveal them,
this must be quite
the serious affair.
Understood, sir.
I will see to it.
We're counting on you, Colonel.
Your orders are as follows.
Retrieve the stolen documents,
and liquidate Irene Adler.
Classified documents?
Intriguing.
Indeed. Apparently, serious
enough to rock the whole nation.
Is there anything else
that we should know?
Any demands made
by this Adler woman?
No. Up to now,
there hasn't been a single
demand issued for their return.
In fact, she's stayed hidden,
without making any contact.
[LOUIS]
She stole something so critical,
yet has made no demands.
It's rather curious,
don't you agree?
[WILHELM] I apologize,
and hope you will forgive me
for arriving in this mask.
I am the King of Bohemia.
Wilhelm Gottsreich Sigismond von
Ormstein, and I seek your help.
You're a king?
Well, that was obvious
the moment you walked in.
Sorry. Under these
circumstances,
I could not very well
send another in my place.
I see, go on.
The whole affair
began five years ago.
It was when I was
staying in Warsaw.
I fell in love with
a beautiful woman.
This woman's name
is Irene Adler.
Yes. It's all
becoming clear now.
Sherlock, do you
know this woman?
I've never actually met her.
But she's famous
in the underworld.
So then, what does
this woman have over you?
She has a photograph.
If anyone were to see,
they might naturally
assume we would be wed.
[HOLMES chuckles]
Oh, you don't say?
I admire this woman's pluck!
So, she's making you pay
for dumping her, is that it?
No! Sherlock, don't do that!
Stop being so boorish!
It just so happens
that I am committed to marry
another woman in
the very near future.
[WATSON gasps]
[WILHELM]
But Adler
has threatened to
send my dear betrothed
the photograph
before our nuptials!
Brilliant! Miss Adler
sounds riveting!
[BOTH]
Uh?
[WILHELM]
Three hundred pounds in gold.
And a note for
another seven hundred.
[WATSON gasps] Why-- Why
that's a thousand pounds!
That would pay our rent for
the next decade, and then some.
[WILHELM]
Here is the woman's address.
I ask you to please
retrieve the photograph.
[WILHELM]
I am glad to have met you.
Good night,
Mister Sherlock Holmes.
[ADLER chuckles] Perhaps I made
that lie a little too elaborate.
And yet... it needed
to be realistic.
[ADLER]
How else would I lead on
the greatest
detective in London?
I hope you'll hurry
and see me soon,
Master Detective Holmes.
[HOLMES]
I apologize for calling so late.
Ahem. Allow me to introduce
myself, Sherlock Holmes,
the consulting detective.
You had some plumbing
work done here recently
if I'm not mistaken.
It seems at some
point during that work,
a criminal wanted for murder
slipped in with the laborers,
and concealed a piece of
evidence within your home.
I ask for your assistance
with the search.
What's this?
A smoke bomb, Watson.
We're going to use it to make
her think the house is on fire.
We're doing what?!
See here, John.
When an unforeseen incident,
such as a house fire occurs,
people instinctively
become concerned
about what they find important.
Don't worry; I've had great
success with this trick before.
[WATSON] Well, everything
depends on how Adler responds.
[HOLMES]
This is a rather urgent matter.
Please help, it shan't take very
long.
[door clicks, opens]
[ADLER] I thought it might be
someone playing a prank on me.
I can scarcely believe the real
Sherlock Holmes is in my house!
I am a great fan of yours,
I'll have you know.
My name is Miss Irene Adler.
[HOLMES] She's not at
all like the profile
I'd envisioned of her.
I never expected her to be such
a light-hearted, cheeky woman.
[ADLER] You haven't found
anything, have you?
Are you certain that miscreant
hid it somewhere in this house?
I am. No question.
[HOLMES]
Go, John!
[HOLMES] Any moment now,
I assure you, I will locate it.
You give me your word
you'll find it?
And you're sure
you're up to the task?
Huh?
You'll never
find it now, Holmes!
I'll burn it all!
[HOLMES wheezes]
[HOLMES]
Confound it!
[HOLMES groans]
She's gone! But where?
[gasps]
Might this be what
you're looking for,
Master Detective?
[HOLMES]
The photo.
Adler knew from the
very beginning exactly
why we came here tonight!
[WATSON] Sherlock!
Have you found the photograph?
[gasps] By Jove, the plan
actually worked!
[HOLMES]
Uh... John...
Your smoke bomb ruse
was perfect! A masterpiece!
Yeah, but behind you!
There's a real fire!
Huh? [yelps] But how?!
It was just a smoke bomb!
I thought you said
this worked before!
[HOLMES] It did! But the woman
seemingly pulled one over on us!
[ADLER]
What a terrible turn of events!
Now the photo you
were searching for
may have been lost in
this blazing inferno.
And either way,
the World's Greatest Detective
will have to answer for this.
Now see here, Sherlock!
What in blazes have
you done this time?!
Uh! Oh.
Who are you?
And you must be,
Sherlock's landlady!
As of today, he and
I'll be living together.
Won't we, Sherly?
[gasps]
[HOLMES grumbles]
Get off!
Why are you suddenly
behaving this way?
It's not like that!
It's actually quite a long
story, Miss Hudson.
[ADLER]
Yes.
He's right.
But to summarize, these two
gentlemen are indebted to me.
I do hope you understand.
What was it? Misses Hudson?
Oh, no. It's "Miss"
and you, Misses?
Adler.
Miss Adler.
Right, lovely.
Might I ask a favor
of you, Miss Hudson?
What favor?
Nothing much.
Do you have some
clothes she might borrow?
My clothes?! Why would I?!
I look a mess.
Like an ash-covered Cinderella
ever since my house burned down.
Misses Hudson,
I hope you won't be
like the cruel step-sisters
in the fairy tale.
[HUDSON growls]
Miss Adler has made
contact with Sherlock Holmes.
Precisely as you
predicted, dear William.
Indeed. Holmes likely
hasn't the faintest notion
that Adler's very
objective in this
is to worm her
way in close to him,
the world's greatest detective,
known throughout all of London.
[LOUIS] The more she
stays in the public eye,
the greater the chance is
that if she were abducted,
or assassinated it would
become a major incident.
Thus, the government's
options are very limited.
Nothing heavy-handed.
Precisely, and likely
what Adler's thinking as well.
This move should
buy her some time.
But will it buy enough for her
to reach the negotiation table?
[HOLMES] What is she
hoping to gain by this?
[HOLMES]
The way things are going,
it will be near impossible
to retrieve the photograph.
The most I can do at this
point is keep an eye on her
to make sure she
doesn't send it.
[HOLMES grunts]
Allow me a little smoke break.
[ADLER]
Fine, if you insist.
But after this, we're heading
straight to Piccadilly Circus.
Whatever you say.
[KATE]
No!
I'm definitely going to
audition for the part!
Oh, that is rich.
Do try to remember something.
The owner of the
theatre is the viscount,
who happens to be
my father. Get it?
Commoners aren't on even
footing with aristocrats.
Which means you'll never be
a star as long as you live.
[GIRL 12A] Doris is right.
Best to remember your place!
[HOLMES sighs]
Should this keep devolving,
they're bound to come
to blows. What a bother.
[KATE]
I don't care.
Everyone's supposed to get
an equal chance to audition.
You really think that?
The reality of it is you never
had a chance to begin with,
poor Kate. How sad.
Because you're scared.
[DORIS grunts]
[KATE] You're just
worried that if I do it,
then the lead will
go to me instead.
Be quiet.
That's the reason you don't
want me to audition, right?
Shut your mouth!
[KATE yelps]
- -[splash]
- -[HOLMES, ADLER gasp]
[gasps, grunts]
[DORIS giggles] Oh, no!
It looks like she can't swim!
The sewage canal is where you
commoners belong, anyway!
What, seriously?
Ugh...
[BOTH gasp]
Adler!
[KATE panting]
[ADLER] Oh, bother.
We're soaked to the skin.
[KATE]
Uh, thank you very much.
But your dress...
Don't worry about it.
Saving your life is
much more important.
But listen.
The theatre is
not as easy a world
as you may like to believe.
[KATE]
Uh?
[ADLER] I have seen far
too many parts go to people
solely due to their connections,
or family standing.
Wait, I know you.
You're the Irene Adler!
[ADLER chuckles]
[GROUP gasps]
[KATE]
Miss Adler! Listen.
I want to become a prima
donna, just like you are!
[ADLER] In that case,
listen to me, Kate.
And remember,
you must prove that you
are the right choice
by letting your own
talent shine through!
And if your skills
are strong enough,
then someone else's
connections won't matter,
and you'll win the day!
[gasps]
[KATE]
Right!
[HOLMES]
Before you catch cold...
[ADLER grunts]
[ADLER chuckles]
Oh, Sherly!
You're all but
naked now, aren't you?
[HOLMES]
Never mind me. Put these on!
[HOLMES] My initial profile of
the woman has been shattered.
She's not the sort of person
who would blackmail the king
of Bohemia over an affair.
After you eliminate
every other possibility,
hen whatever remains,
must be the truth
no matter how improbable.
We've arrived, Irene.
It's time to wake up!
[ADLER grunts]
[yawns]
[ADLER, ALBERT grunt]
[ALBERT]
Pardon me.
Miss... Adler.
Don't stand around! Come inside.
Right. [grunts]
[ADLER gasps]
[MYCROFT] Next time
on Moriarty The Patriot  ,
"A Scandal in the
British Empire: Act Two."